{
    "id": "ba1a5b60e54d411ea2ce23e85efe6afe",
    "title": "Types Of Subordinate Clauses",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "They serve God well who serve His children.",
            "description": "Here the adjective clause ‘who serve His children’ modifies the noun God.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "cef929ad4dd944009df67f8093f23157"
        },
        {
            "question": "Quarrels won’t last long if the fault is only on one side.",
            "description": "Here the subordinate adverb clause ‘if the fault is only on one side’ modifies the verb ‘last long’.",
            "answers": [
                "Adverb clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Noun clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "4df45888d77c4a9ab2c6f726bd9427ce"
        },
        {
            "question": "That you should say so surprises me.",
            "description": "A noun clause can be the subject of a verb. Here the noun clause ‘that you should say so’ is the subject of the verb ‘surprises’.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adverb clause",
                "Adjective clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c49613eac23c4adc8fc3881fedbd268c"
        },
        {
            "question": "Your statement that you found the money in the closet cannot be believed.",
            "description": "Here the noun clause ‘that you found the money in the closet’ is in apposition to the noun ‘statement’. Only noun clauses can be used like this.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "4922655459a94ed88001b658bd548e13"
        },
        {
            "question": "I asked the boy how old he was.",
            "description": "Here the noun clause ‘how old he was’ is the object of the verb asked.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "4b4e9d40a94b4b25b642532580bd2b98"
        },
        {
            "question": "Uneasy lies the head that wears the crown.",
            "description": "Here the adjective clause ‘that wears the crown’ modifies the noun head. Adjective clauses modify nouns and give additional information about them.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adverb clause",
                "Adjective clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "aade0517da3748eba0b61b6542be98de"
        },
        {
            "question": "Youth is the time when the seeds of character are sown.",
            "description": "Here the adjective clause when the seeds of character are sown modifies the noun time.",
            "answers": [
                "Adverb clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Noun clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "6e66d9bda42b404097407a87037326f7"
        },
        {
            "question": "Servants who are honest are trusted.",
            "description": "Here the adjective clause ‘who are honest’ modifies the noun servants.",
            "answers": [
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause",
                "Noun clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "843b3077aab047b3bab11824f65ed518"
        },
        {
            "question": "Because I like you, I shall help you.",
            "description": "An adverb clause of reason expresses the reason for the action mentioned in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Adverb clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Noun clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "91da98fc069849158388220781345678"
        },
        {
            "question": "The dog followed the boy wherever he went.",
            "description": "Here the adverb clause of place ‘wherever he went’ modifies the verb ‘followed’.",
            "answers": [
                "Adjective clause",
                "Noun clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "a92ebb014edd46eca690ec21ca0f5992"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I like it, I will buy it.",
            "description": "Adverb clauses of condition are usually introduced by the conjunctions if, whether or unless.",
            "answers": [
                "Adjective clause",
                "Noun clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "3c42c7e3e7654d4db154e88e159ce701"
        },
        {
            "question": "They spoke in a low voice so that the child would not wake up.",
            "description": "Here the adverb clause ‘so that the child would not wake up’ expresses the purpose of the action mentioned in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause",
                "Noun clause"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "aabff7656417426a8d8c5565c3d1616e"
        }
    ]
}